Le filtre Courbe dans GIMP
a récemment obtenu plusieurs améliorations utiles.
Vous y aurez accès
quand GIMP 2.10.12 sera déployé
c'est à dire bientôt.
Le changement le plus visible est la saisie numérique
to set coordinates of points on the curve.
It works just as expected:
cliquez pour sélectionner un point,
then edit its coordinates right here.
The other big change is the newly introduced
sharp type of points.
This allows making sharp
rather than smooth transitions,
and you can combine sharp and smooth points
on a single curve
cliquez pour sélectionner un point,
ensuite cliquez ici pour sélectionner le type de point.
Speaking of which,
now when you click to select a point on a curve,
GIMP fait de son mieux pour ne pas le déplacer.
De plus, quand vous appuyez sur la touche Ctrl
while adding or dragging a point on a curve,
the point will snap
to the original segment of the curve,
and all the changes will be very slight.
This is great for cases
when you need to add a bunch of points to a curve
and deal with them later.
Finally, when you hover the mouse pointer
over the curve point
or drag that point,
the dialog will display the curve point's coordinates
rather than mouse pointer coordinates.
All in all, a bunch of very useful changes
that improve GIMP's user experience.